Fear the man with nothing left to lose.
The Rover is a crime, drama film directed by David Michôd.
Ten years after a severe economic collapse in the western
world, lawlessness reigns and life is cheap.
Eric is a lone drifter, and his car is his only possession.
When a gang steals it, Eric comes across the injured
Rey, left behind by the car thieves.
The pair form an unlikely and uneasy alliance.
Eric, played by Guy Pearce.
Rey, played by Robert Pattinson.
Henry, played by Scoot McNairy.
Archie, played by David Field.
Dorothy Peeples, played by Susan Prior.
Sgt. Rickofferson, played by Anthony Hayes.
The Rover is a 2014 Australian dystopian Western drama film written and directed
by David Michôd and based on a story by Michôd and Joel Edgerton.
It is a contemporary Western taking place in the Australian
outback, ten years after a global economic collapse.
The film stars Guy Pearce and Robert Pattinson, and features Scoot McNairy,
David Field, Anthony Hayes, Gillian Jones, and Susan Prior.
It premiered out of competition in the Midnight Screenings section
at the 2014 Cannes Film Festival on 18 May 2014.
The film screened at the 2014 Sydney Film Festival on 7 June 2014, followed by
the theatrical release of film in Australia on 12 June 2014.
It had a limited release on 13 June 2014 in New York City and Los Angeles
before expanding wide on 20 June 2014 in the United States.
The film earned seven nominations at the 4th AACTA Awards: Best Direction, Best Lead Actor for Guy Pearce, Best Supporting Actor for Robert
Pattinson, Best Production Design, Best Original Music Score, Best Supporting Actress for Susan Prior, and Best Sound, winning the last two.
The film explores themes of australia, small town,
sibling relationship, hostage, dystopia.
The tone is emotional.